#### Contact

5516662661 (Mobile) hernandez.yohan@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/yohan-hernandez-71497561 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Microsoft Office Customer Service Hospitals

# Yohan Hernandez

RN Cardiac Cath Lab at Mount Sinai St. Luke's New York, New York

## Summary

Account Manager at Skymed Solutions.

Cath Lab & Operating Room Traveler.

Epic Go-Live Consultant, RN Super User (Op-time, Anesthesia care, Cupid)

Take care of people with cardiovascular diseases and disorders. When cardiovascular problems require surgery and special care. EP procedural Experience

Assist, circulate and scrub within the cardiovascular lab, help patients later with recovering their mobility and strength.

teach patients and families about cardiovascular disease prevention, symptoms, and treatments.

Page 1 of 4

RN Operating Room Circulator, General Surgery, Orthopaedics, OBGYN, Robotic Surgery, Plastic Surgery, Urology surgery

Multifaceted Structured Patient-facing

Florida Multi-State Nursing license New York RN License New Jersey RN License

# Experience

New York-Presbyterian Hospital
Cardiac Catheterization Laboratory Nurse
January 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months)
Greater New York City Area

Mount Sinai St. Luke's RN Cardiac Cath Lab February 2019 - August 2019 (7 months) New York

Intro procedure, pre procedure and post procedure cardiac cath RN.

Interfaith Medical Center
Travel RN Cath Lab/IR
June 2018 - February 2019 (9 months)
Brooklyn, New York

Cardiac cath lab RN

Northwestern Memorial Hospital Epic RN Trainer February 2018 - May 2018 (4 months) Chicago, Illinois

Anesthesia, Cupid, Optime Epic Trainer

HCA East Florida Division
Cardiac cath lab
January 2016 - February 2018 (2 years 2 months)
Miami, Florida

Northwest Medical Center
Cardiac cath lab RN
August 2017 - January 2018 (6 months)
margate, florida

Cardiac Cath Lab intra-procedure circulator

Baptist health south
Cath lab registered nurse
March 2017 - July 2017 (5 months)
Jacksonville, Florida

Pre procedure, intra procedure, post procedure, monitoring procedures using Merge system in the cardiac cath lab, travel RN

Memorial Healthcare System
1 year 3 months
Cardiac cath RN

September 2016 - March 2017 (7 months)

Flamingo road florida

Operating Room Nurse January 2016 - March 2017 (1 year 3 months) Oneblood

Donor services specialist

April 2014 - May 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Florida

Customer service and direct interactions with donors, phlebotomy specialist, apheresis plasma and platelets procedures as per company's policy

Servimed JJ Johnson & Johnson campany

Perioperative Nurse, OR Nurse, Aesthetic Nurse, clinical asesor, and medical seller

April 2010 - March 2013 (3 years)

Traumatology and orthopedic surgery, knowledge in the nursing process for perioperative traumatology patients, patients care and recovery

Total knee, hip, shoulder transplant and the management for all kind of fractures

#### **CPV**

RN intensive care unit, Cath lab RN August 2006 - March 2013 (6 years 8 months)

Venezuela

Assist with angioplasties, valvuloplasties and stent placementsHelp implant pacemakers and implantable cardioverter-defibiliators (ICDs)

diagnoses cardiac conditions with an invasive catheterization procedure.

assists physicians in the diagnosis and treatment of cardiac conditions.

prepare patients for catheterization, angioplasty, pacemaker implantation and cardiac procedures. Preparation of patients can include taking the patient's vital signs, oxygen levels and heart rhythm before the physician examines the patient.

help ease the patient's fear and answer questions regarding the cardiac procedure.

begin an intravenous line while preparing patients for a catheterization or cardiac procedure.

assist physicians during catheterization procedures, angioplasties, pacemaker implantation and other cardiac procedures.

administer medication according to the physician's instructions before, during and after cardiac procedures.

assist during emergencies and perform lifesaving procedures.

monitor patients during their recovery in the cardiac cath lab, monitoring the patient's vital signs, administering medications and updating the patient's chart.

be prepared to administer treatment if patients experience excessive bleeding, fever or other side effects from the cardiac procedure.

provide instructions and education to patients and their families before discharge from the cardiac cath lab. Education and instruction can include information on medications, nutrition and care of a surgical site.

### Education

Chamberlain University

Master's degree, Family Practice Nurse/Nursing · (2018 - 2020)

Chamberlain College of Nursing

Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse (2016 - 2017)

fundacion universidad de carabobo

Perioperative nurse/ OR nurse, Orthopaedic nurse · (2010 - 2011)

universidad nacional experimental Romulo Gallegos UNERG Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2006 - 2008)

IUTEPAL instituto universitario de tecnologia juan pablo perez alfonzo

Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2003 - 2006)